shu.ac.uk 2017-01-28

# Privacy policy | Sheffield Hallam University

This website (www.shu.ac.uk) is run by Sheffield Hallam University. The privacy of our users is important to us and the University takes care to safeguard it. This policy explains why and how we collect and use your personal data via the website. It also covers the personal data that we collect from enquirers by phone, email, and voicemail.

We may change this policy by updating the information on this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes that we make. This policy is effective from 1 January 2009 (last revised April 2016).

## 1\. Use of information provided by visitors

The University uses personal data for a variety of purposes, however, your personal information is never sold to any third party.

**a) Enquiries (i.e. requesting publications, registering for open days, enquiring about courses or events etc.)**

You may be asked to provide your name, email address or other personal information on various pages on our site in order that your enquiry can be dealt with. You may also provide this information by phone, email or in a voicemail message.

The University seeks to respond in an appropriate, timely, and effective way when dealing with enquiries and applications and uses a customer relationship management (CRM) system to support this service. This means that you will not have to repeat all the details of a previous enquiry: each time you contact us we will be picking up where you left off. It also means that we can improve the information that we provide about our courses, services and processes in future.

We may use mailing houses to process certain mailings and external research agencies to carry out market research on the University's behalf. The University ensures that such agencies will also handle information securely and in accordance with the Data Protection Act.

We will use any demographic information you provide for market research purposes (in aggregate form only). These statistics will not include any information that could be used to identify any individual. From time to time we may contact individuals and invite them to provide feedback on their experiences and impressions of the University. This helps us to improve our services.

Where appropriate for bookings relating to our outreach activity, we may also store information provided on a separate secure database, to be used for research and evaluation purposes. More information can be found here.

When you provide this information you are asked whether you wish to receive any further promotional information from Sheffield Hallam University. If you choose not to receive further information we will only use your name and address details to respond to your enquiry, unless you

  * are a current student, in which case we will continue to use your personal data for student administration purposes, or
  * you have opted to receive information about alumni services and/or University events.

If you choose to receive further information from Sheffield Hallam University, you may change your mind at any time by writing to us or emailing us using the following contact details

Marketing Directorate  
Sheffield Hallam University  
City Campus  
Sheffield  
S1 1WB  
Email [creativedigital@shu.ac.uk](mailto:creativedigital@shu.ac.uk)

**b) Subscription services**

You may use our subscription facility to receive regular email updates or SMS text messages from Sheffield Hallam University. Any information you supply for this is used only to deliver messages based on the subjects you choose to the email address or phone number you specify. You may unsubscribe at any time. Details of how to stop receiving updates are provided at the time of subscribing and on the relevant web pages.

**c) Online Store**

You will need to register as a customer to order goods and services from our Online Store. Further information about how we use customer information and about our Online Store provider and secure payment service provider is available on our Online Store site.

**d) Online community**

The University's online community for alumni, friends and business colleagues of the University has its own terms and conditions in addition to this privacy policy. The information you provide via the online community will be used primarily for communication with members of the University and the online community. More information is provided in the [terms and conditions](http://netcommunity.shu.ac.uk/page.aspx?pid=199) and on the [online community website.](https://netcommunity.shu.ac.uk/sslpage.aspx?pid=213&bm=1932899202)

**e) Reporting a fault, giving feedback, making a complaint**

If you contact us by email or through a web page to request information, report a problem or provide feedback on our services we will use the information you provide to respond to your message, to address the issue you have raised, and to make improvements to our services. We do not use this information for other purposes.

**f) Responding to enquiries or concerns relating to law enforcement, fraud and safeguarding issues.**

The University will provide information to law enforcement or regulatory bodies where this is required or allowed under the relevant legislation.

## 2\. Security

We have appropriate physical, electronic and organisational security measures in place in order to protect against the loss, theft, misuse or alteration of information we collect from you online.

These security measures include the necessary protection to prevent, as far as possible, access to your information by parties other than Sheffield Hallam University.

## 3\. Cookies

Please see our How we use cookies page to find out how cookies are used on this website.

## 4\. Data Protection Act

Information will be used in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and other applicable legislation. The University is registered as a Data Controller with the Information Commissioner. [Our register entry can be viewed here.](https://ico.org.uk/about-the-ico/what-we-do/register-of-data-controllers/)

The University's Data Protection Policy Statement is also [available and can be viewed here.](https://students.shu.ac.uk/regulations/index.html) You can also see how we use students' personal data.

## 5\. Access to personal information

Under the Data Protection Act 1998 you have the right to request copies of all the personal data that the University holds about you. This is called a Subject Access Request and must be submitted in writing along with a £10 fee. More information about making a Subject Access Request is available here.

For enquiries about Subject Access Requests or if you have a Data Protection query or complaint, please email [foi@shu.ac.uk.](mailto:foi@shu.ac.uk.)

_Sheffield Hallam University is not responsible for the content of external websites_
